(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners, welcome back.
We are here at English
Pod, I am joined with Erika.
- And my partner in crime, Marco.
- All right, so today
we're gonna be talking
about a really great topic,
one of my favorites, beer.
- Beer.
So beer is a very popular drink,
especially in bars and when you go out.
- Yes, it's very common
with students, I think.
- Yes, and it's also not very
strong like a vodka or whiskey.
- Yes.
- Okay, so we are going
to be at a bar today
and we're going to be looking at some
of this vocabulary that you would find.
- Yes, I mean, you've got
to know this beer vocabulary.
(laughs)
- Okay, so let's listen to
our dialogue for the first time
and then we'll come back
and look at these words.
(upbeat music)
- Come on, what do you have on top?
- High and a kid and Budweiser.
We have a two for one happy hour special.
- Cool, give me a pint of high
and a kid and a half a pint of bud.
- Okay, find a high and a kid
and half a pint of bud for table six.
- What about some appetizers?
- Sure, let's have some, let's have
some nachos and mozzarella sticks.
- Okay, that'll be 80 bucks.
- Huh, what?
(upbeat music)
- Well, it's pretty expensive
for two beers and some food.
- Yes, well, it happens
sometimes you go to these very
exclusive bars and they
charge you like if it was gold.
- I mean, that's crazy.
Well, let's take a
look at some of these
great words that we
saw in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
Our first word is on tap.
- On tap, on tap.
- So he asked, what do you have on tap?
Now this is a strange sentence,
what exactly does it mean?
- Okay, well, he's asking
about what beers the bar has.
- But not in a bottle
or not in a can, right?
- Right, so you know, in a
bar, there's often this machine,
that will pour very fresh beer,
right, directly into the glass.
- Into the glass, mm-hmm.
- Yeah, this is a very popular thing
because like you say, it's fresh beer.
- Yeah, it tastes better, it tastes better.
- Okay, so what do you have on tap?
- What do you have on tap?
- All right, let's take a look
at a second word, happy hour.
- Happy hour, happy hour, happy hour.
- Now this is very common
and popular with bars.
- Yes.
- What is it when they have a happy hour?
- Okay, a happy hour is a period of
time where the drinks are very cheap.
- Okay, so happy hour could be from 5 p.m.
till 10 p.m.
50% off.
- So if the drink is $4, then
it is now $2 in a happy hour.
- Not happy, perfect.
- And this brings us to
our third word, a special.
- A special, a special, a special.
- So this is a noun, and what does it mean
when a restaurant or a bar has a special?
- It's like they're having a sale.
- A sale, so things are cheaper.
- So it could be, for example,
a Monday night special.
- Or like in the dialogue,
a happy hour special.
- Okay, so it is a promotion.
- Yes.
- All right, very good.
And now they ordered a pint of Hayneken
and half a pint of Budweiser, pint.
- This is a very, very special beer word.
So a pint is the size of your glass.
- Okay, so we understand
how much a pint is.
Well, what would be
the equivalent in leaders?
- A pint is 0.4 liters.
- Okay, so almost half a liter is one pint.
- Yes.
- Okay, it is very common when you go
into a bar, you can order a pint of beer.
- Yes, exactly.
In English, we don't say
I'll have half a liter of beer.
- Right, right.
So let's take a look at our next
word on language takeaway.
- Epitizers.
- Appitizers.
- Okay, so what is an appetizer?
- Well, it is food you eat before
your dinner or before your lunch.
- Okay, so it's usually maybe like a
salad or a soup or something small
that you can eat right
before your big meal.
- Okay, so some common appetizers at
a bar and we saw them in our dialogue,
nachos and mozzarella
sticks, nachos, nachos, nachos.
So nachos are little chips, right?
- Yeah, corn chips and it has cheese and
maybe some tomatoes and maybe some beans.
- Okay, so those are nachos, they're
very common in the United States.
- Yes, yeah.
- And what about mozzarella sticks?
- Mozzarella sticks, a travesty on the
world and humanity and everyone's arteries.
- Well, mozzarella is a cheese, right?
mozzarella cheese and this cheese
is, what is it, how is it prepared?
- You put it in some bread
crumbs and then you fry it in oil.
You deep fry it.
- And you don't like this?
- No, this is terrible.
- Well, hi, they're so good.
- Oh my god.
- 'Cause then you can dip it
in a little sauce - Oh, delicious.
- Marco, there are so many
reasons why this is wrong.
- All right, well, mozzarella sticks.
They're a very popular bar food.
- All right, well, why don't
we listen to the dialogue again
and we'll be able to hear these
words in context at a slower speed.
(upbeat music)
- Hey, man, what do you have on top?
- Hine a can and Budweiser.
We have a two for one happy hour special.
- Cool, give me a pint of Hine
a can and half a pint of Bud.
- Okay.
- Pardon to hide again?
Half a pint of Bud for table six.
- What about some appetizers?
- Sure, let's have some, let's have
some nachos and mozzarella sticks.
- Okay, that'll be 80 bucks.
- Wha, what?
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so we saw some really
good vocabulary words there
and now let's take a
look at putting it together.
- We're putting it together.
- Well, in this lesson,
we are going to look
at one phrase that
sometimes causes problems.
- So let's listen to this phrase
that we're talking about.
What about some appetizers?
- Okay, so this phrase, what about?
- Yeah, I often hear people
use it to ask a question.
So a common mistake is
asking, what about your weekend?
- What about your new job?
Now, this is incorrect, right?
- You cannot use the phrase,
what about to ask a question
about information, so you
cannot ask for information.
- Okay, because in our dialogue, the bartender
said, and what about some appetizers?
- Right, because he is making a suggestion.
- Right, so he's saying, well,
why don't you have some food?
- Yes, the phrase, what about
can be used to make a suggestion?
- Okay, so I can say, what
about going to the movies?
- Mm-hmm, you know
what, let's hear a few more
examples of this, 'cause
I think it's really useful.
- Example one, what
about these dirty clothes?
You said you would wash them days ago?
- Example two, what about
going to the mall instead?
- I'm tired of going to the movies.
Example three, what about
a pizza instead of noodles?
- All right, so really good examples, and
the same thing we can apply to, how about?
- Exactly, so again, how about,
cannot ask for information.
- Okay.
- So you can't say how about your boss?
- All right, perfect.
Okay, so let's listen to
this dialogue one last time,
and then we'll come back and talk a
little bit more about ours and beers.
- Hey man, what do you have on top?
- Honey can and Budweiser.
We have a two for one, happy hour special.
- Cool, give me a pint of
honey can and half a pint of bud.
- Okay, pint of honey can,
half pint of bud for table six?
What about some appetizers?
- Sure, let's have some, let's have
some nachos and mozzarella sticks.
- Okay, that'll be 80 bucks.
- What?
- Well Marco, I know
you're a big fan of beer,
and actually I think everyone
here at practice is a big beer drinker.
- And this is the perfect opportunity
to tell everyone about the
world-renowned beer shake.
- Oh my god.
Okay Marco.
- All right, so everyone that listens
to this recipe is a non-believer.
They say that it is not
possible for it to taste good.
- Okay.
- But here's the recipe.
You take a liter of beer
or maybe half a liter.
So a pint, a pint or a pint and a
half, and you put it in the blender.
- Okay.
- All right.
Now you take two eggs, uh-huh.
- Okay, not cooked, not boiled, anything.
You take two eggs and
put them in the blender.
It could be one or two.
- Okay.
- And then you take about half a
cup of sugar, put it in the blender.
- What?
- And you mix all that together,
and you get this really good
foamy, delicious beer shake.
- So a beer milkshake.
- Well it has no milk, but
it's actually really good.
I've prepared it for some people.
They're like, no, that's not possible.
It can't taste good.
And in the end they're like,
wow, this is actually pretty good.
- So did you invent this recipe?
- It's actually really
common in Ecuador and Peru.
I've even seen it in Chile,
usually with a dark beer.
- Okay.
- Right?
- So like a Guinness, or?
- It could be a Guinness, or yeah, if it's
that, a dark beer is a little bit sweeter.
So you wouldn't add so much sugar,
but if you have another
beer like a lager or a stout,
you could still do it, but
just add a little bit more sugar
because that beer is
a little bit more bitter.
- Okay, well I am not
going to try this recipe,
but maybe you guys are.
- You should, try it out and
let me know how it works.
- Yeah, you can tell us all about
it on our website, EnglishPod.
com.
- Yeah, and we're definitely
there to answer all your questions
and I'll be posting the
recipe as well on the website.
- All right, well, we're
out of time for today,
but thanks for listening
and until next time, bye.
(upbeat music)